

# Sasidhar Reddy N

A multi-faceted software developer with over 6 years of experience who is knowledgeable in Java 11, Data Structures and Algorithms, Multithreading, Spring Boot, Micronaut, Microservices, MySQL, RESTful Web Services, Docker, Kubernetes and Helm. I am looking for individual contributor roles in product companies.

sasidhar996@gmail.com

+91 9943795897



Bengaluru, Karnataka, India in



## **Work Experience**



#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER • Nexthink

August 2021 - Present

- Worked on Nexthink content management system web service for delivering library packs to customers.
- · I was involved in bootstrapping a new microservice called Content Administration for unifying the user experience for all the products at Nexthink.
- Actively involved in clarifying requirements from PM, coding, testing and deploying features on the cloud(AWS).
- Design, implement, deliver and validate Nexthink digital experience features.
- Deployed Micronaut based micro services in Amazon Kubernetes Service(EKS) using Jenkins, Terraform and Helm.
- Developed unit test cases and mock testing using JUNIT.
- Implemented and maintained monitoring and alerting of production and corporate servers using New Relic.
- Contribute to the overall product's architecture and design (including storage strategies)



#### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER • Blackhawk Network

April 2021 - August 2021

- · Worked on the O2 mobile rewards program, where rewards are calculated for customers based on the top-
- Developed REST based services based on struts framework for O2 rewards.



### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER · Software AG

January 2016 - April 2021

- Involved in the design and development of Spring Boot Cloud applications hosted on AWS.
- Developed critical features involving distributed caches and queues like Redis and Kafka.
- Work and collaborate with enterprise and technical architects in the process of low and high level solution, design, troubleshooting issues, seeing problems through to resolution.
- · Responsibility for capacity planning and estimation for Sprint.
- Investigate and research tools and technologies for achieving goals.
- Help facilitate software quality measures TDD, Peer Review and Pair Programming.
- · Communicate effectively with team members, customers and stakeholders.

- Involved in development and deployment of features like Streaming Restful Web Services , Git HA, Connector microservices , Cloud Monitoring APIs etc.
- Involved in handling customer escalations and cloud on call support.

## Education



2011 - 2015

# Maharaja Engineering College

**Computer Science** 

Tools and Applications
<ul> <li>IDEs like Eclipse , Intellij</li> <li>Git</li> <li>Putty, MobaXterm</li> <li>Filezilla, WinSCP</li> <li>WinMerge, Beyond compare</li> <li>Editors like Notepad++</li> <li>Postman , Burp Suite</li> <li>MySQL workbench</li> <li>New Relic</li> <li>JMeter</li> <li>BloomRPC</li> <li>K9s</li> </ul>

Powered by CakeResume